Duncan Crawbuck

(925) 548-7020 duncan@crawbuck.com linkedin.com/in/dcrawbuck crawbuck.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Recent graduate with experience building mobile and web applications. Enthusiastic about learning and mastering new languages and concepts. Focused on using breakthrough technology to create powerful experiences and solve difficult problems. Experienced with Agile software development and remote collaboration. Works well in fast-paced, collaborative environments.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

May 2020, 3.5 GPA

California State University, Sacramento

Dean's Honor List, cum laude

Relevant Course Work

- Advanced Algorithm Design & Analysis

- Computing Theory & Programming Languages

- Compiler Construction

- Operating System Principles

- Database Management Systems

- Computer Networks and Internets

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Swift, C/C++, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks UIKit, SwiftUI, React

Database MySQL

Software Xcode, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Vim

Development Tools Git, Scrum

EXPERIENCE

Simple & Classic Games

July 2019 - Present

Independent iOS Developer

simpleandclassicga.me

- Developed games including Solitaire and Minesweeper and sold them on the iOS and Mac App Store.
- Used SwiftUI, Mac Catalyst, and UIKit to build modern and powerful applications.
- Utilized automated testing, continuous deployment, and TestFlight beta testing.

Fire & Risk Alliance Sprinkler Database

September 2019 - May 2020

CSUS Senior Project

sprinklerdb.com

- A year-long Scrum-based team project to develop and deliver software following client specification.
- Delivered a React web application to navigate and compare dynamic visualizations from a MongoDB database with user login and authentication.
- Led the implementation of an interactive d3.js visualization in the React application.
- Attended biweekly end-of-sprint meetings with the client (Fire & Risk Alliance) and a faculty advisor.

Baby C Compiler April 2020 - May 2020

CSC 151 (Compiler Construction) Project

Github Repo

- Developed a compiler to parse simplified C-style code and produce assembly code.
- Generates an abstract syntax tree and fills a symbol table for declared variables.
- Built to handle variable declarations, expressions, if/else statements, and while loops.

Pirex – Information Retrieval Tool

October 2018 - December 2018

CSC 131 (Computer Software Engineering) Project

GitHub Repo

- A collaborative group project developing software according to a provided specification.
- Developed a Java-based document indexer and search application with a graphical user interface.
- Personally oversaw the use of the Scrum process and shared version control.